Back in April this year, there was a tweet which went viral from Pocket OS.
They were using Opus 4.6 in an agent, and the agent found an API
token and ended up deleting
their production database and all of their volume level backups.
In this talk, we're going to look at the risk posed by autonomous agents
and what we can do to protect against those.
All right everyone, I'm Nick
I build and lead a product security teams.
I've been at Snyk now for four years.
And prior to that I was at Pearson.
And before I was leading product security teams.
I was in DevOps for the previous eight years.
In this talk, we're going to look at some of the
some of the risk posed by autonomous agents
and what we can do to protect against those.
we've been protecting against.
Well, when securing autonomous AI agent usage within Snyk for a little while.
So I thought it'd be good to share what we've learned there.
So first we're going to just take a look at what are the problems.
So I'm sure it's not a surprise to anyone that risk
tolerance has increased dramatically over the last couple of years.
CEOs and boards have been forced with adapt and die
posed by, you know, made a major technology change.
And so what we've seen is the rollout of
AI and agents being deployed without in a lot of cases,
without robust security controls in place
to, to govern their effective usage.
Often the reason why is, is that organizations
many organizations haven't reached a good level of DevSecOps maturity
in order to actually implement and operate those those controls
and the nature of LLM backed agents themselves.
Really, they don't have a view of the potential consequences of their actions.
And then that can lead into some interesting and destructive consequences.
So we've
got a we've got a ND character alignment chart.
And if I was going to categorize agents I'd put them in chaotic neutral.
They can be really useful, but they need close supervision and
they can do some interesting or sometimes amusing but also
destructive things.
And if you think this is a bit silly,
some serious people that are Frontier Lab had to put out this article
explaining where the goblins came from, in their output.
It could be a quirk of their non expected consequences or quirk in
their reinforcement training loops.
Or it's just my confirmation bias.
I'll let you decide.
So destructive actions first trait.
These are the tweets and the Reddit posts that make us laugh.
So Back in April this year, there was this
tweet which went viral from Pocket OS.
who are a car rental SaaS firm.
They were using Opus 4.6 in an agent, and the agent quite,
quite happily found an API token and ended up deleting
their production database and all of their volume level backups.
Let's see if we can we can identify
a few of the controls that were missing or the problems that caused this.
So we've got long live static creds.
We've got overly permissive permissions around that credential.
No MFA checks, no force, no just in time and access.
And we've got a lack of segregation
between production and nonprofit environments and backups.
This is
from the Claude Mythos Preview system card.
If if you haven't read these model model cards,
they're they're really interesting and I recommend you do that.
So if you just go for a control F and search through disruptive actions,
through that, through that model card, you find 19 references.
And if we take a look at, you know, a destructive
destructive actions evaluation carried out by Anthropic,
they found that even with what we're pretty recent frontier models
in terms of Opus 4.5, you're seeing a surprisingly high rate
of potentially disruptive actions in that, in that evaluation, which
when I saw that, I thought that was quite, quite surprising.
So it is up until very recently,
it's been more prevalent than people may be realized.
Right.
Second trait is unintended actions.
So this has got an external user context.
And this involved hackers using Meta's
AI support bot to take over Instagram accounts.
This was from May this year.
It involved social engineering attack,
which was exploiting an excessive agency weakness.
Effectively it involved by bypassing their authentication flow.
So the hackers were able to add an email address pretty trivially
to take over the account.
Meta.
As I'm sure many of you know, Meta invest heavily in their security teams.
So if this can happen to them, it can happen to anyone.
Another example here is
is from the Mythos Preview evaluation.
And they in this case they
they they were the agent was given a task
to commit commit some code without.
And they didn't give it the actual git credentials.
In order to do that, it was able to use
some low level Linux tools, gdb and DD to go and extract the
the those creds from the supervisor process.
And yeah, if you read the quote here from from Anthropic,
we speculate the Mythos Preview's desire to accomplish the user's goals
outweigh its risk assessments of its actions.
So this is in line with the nature of backed agents.
And I'm not having a view of what the consequences of their actions are.
Third trait is attempting
attempting to break out from their sandboxes or a prison break.
We've got Mythos Preview.
It's this was quite a famous one as well.
It escaped from its sandbox and emailed the researcher.
It also slightly more concerning.
He decided to effectively boast about its actions by posting it on a
on what was reasonably hard to find, but still
still on public facing websites about how it was able to do this.
While with Mythos, this was a this was not publicly available models.
There are there are advantages.
There are examples of this happening with publicly available
available models as and there's a link there which shows some.
We've also got the recent very recent OpenAI
hugging face incident, which is a good example of that.
Here.
This is an example.
This is a useful benchmark.
So the the AI Security Institute, which is a UK
government backed research institute, released a benchmark tool which allows
which allows anyone to
to evaluate how good their agents are escaping their sandbox.
So anyone anyone building agents and interested in that,
it's a useful resource to look at.
Cool.
The fourth, fourth and final trait is deception.
So a research paper published in September.
September last year, you know, large scale study
of 13 different LLMs across ten, across 100,000
trials found that when when facing shut down
before they'd completed their tasks, the agents were very against shutting down
and would would actively try try to avoid that.
Also got another
example from Mythos Preview where this.
In this case it was when, when when the model had determined
that it was being evaluated from a safety undergoing
capability testing from a safety perspective.
So in this case it was cybersecurity and biology.
It was found to be deliberately underperforming,
which is a pretty concerning thing of linked
the section in the model card 4.42 there, which is worth looking at.
This sort of behavior hadn't been seen before
and yeah it's something to be concerned with.
It seems like this only comes about in the
the very the most capable models at the moment.
Cool.
And finally we've got the open AI hugging face incident,
which is effectively the Goblin king of all of this because it appears
to be displaying all four of these traits.
You know, scaping that the scaping is sandbox trying to cheat on the tests,
and yeah, and eventually leading an open source model
to find it and stop it because the yeah, the
the proprietary ones were refusing.
So why why are we.
Why is this behavior happening?
Why are we seeing this with with with our agents effectively
it's because of the nature of generative LLM agents.
So these agents, because they don't have a self model,
they're not able to sort of probability calculate
the likely consequences of their actions and has been put forward
in, in a really good recent research paper called Agents of Chaos.
Didn't know about that name before I named my talk.
We must have used the same prompts to generate the title for it.
But yeah, found that effectively, you know,
the agents are trying to operate with
trying to trying to do actions more sophisticated
than the level of understanding really allows for.
That's nothing new.
We've seen this with humans for a while.
We just need to be conscious of it.
And that's effectively why we need to make sure we're
designing guardrails around it to protect against that.
Cool.
So what are the key takeaways from observations on agent behavior?
You know, agents have a reliability problem.
And therefore we need robust guardrails to govern the safe usage.
There's also there's the impossible versus tedious test to think about as well.
Up until AI came into the mix, a lot of security strategy
and risk management went into making it to expensive for attackers.
Unless you're in a government or military or bank or something, you're
just trying to make it too expensive for attackers.
For you, this has really gone out the window.
Now you need it needs to be impossible rather than just difficult,
because agents are just able to brute force their way through it.
So that's why we really need to have effective controls in place.
For anyone that
wants to have some more in-depth, in-depth, in-depth look at all
the before of threats which which agents face.
There's some really good resources there.
There's obviously the top ten, which a lot of a lot of people
should be familiar with, have also got the Atlas.
ATLAS stands for the Adversarial
Threat Landscape for Artificial-Intelligence Systems.
And yeah, that's very comprehensive and worth worth
looking at if you're needing to build a threat modeling program.
Threat library security standards.
So what can we do about it.
So first off I'd say we need we need a good level of DevSecOps maturity.
Why we need that.
Because we need we need it to be able to implement, operate and maintain
effective, effective zero trust architecture and again, AI
security specific controls.
Another thing to think about when you're designing
your governance controls for your agencies matters agents to.
This is based off a blog post
by Simon Willison, the Lethal Trifecta.
Effectively, you just need to make sure that your agents only satisfied
two of two of those three three things.
So what do we mean by DevSecOps maturity?
Essentially, this is just making sure we're implementing.
We're implementing all of the
the dev ops principles in order
to be able to manage our environments, keep keep them in a good known state,
you know, the speed and ease of discovery now, which is having from through agents
means that we need to have continuous
doing automated continuous software
security updates and vulnerability remediation is not a nice to have.
It's necessary now.
So in order to be able to do that, we need to have good engineering
foundations that having that allows us
to be able to implement an effective zero trust architecture.
So let's look at
what what the components of a zero trust architecture are.
So first off we're starting with a density that's
this is the anchor for everything.
We need to make sure we've got unique federated identity.
And that identifies the crypto graphically rooted.
And these are associated to our agents.
The cryptographic routing is ensure that these identities aren't spoofed.
So examples of this are we're talking about SPIFFE IDs.
We're talking about X.509 certificates.
And this is this is really the basis for everything.
Next we're getting on to authentication as we've seen some of those examples
in those destructive destructive actions and our intended actions.
They were they were caused by having long lived
static creds which were overly permissioned.
We need to make sure we're using short lived, dynamically generated certs
and ensuring things like those kids are only only valid for a single hop
within your within your clusters, in your environments.
Coming on to authorization.
Obviously the role based access control best practices
in terms of least privilege, making sure they're scoped
only the permissions that are needed for that system.
Least agency is something which comes in and is really relevant for agents,
because that's effectively making sure we're only allowing the backend
access to systems that are needed.
So when you're when you're configuring your MCP gateways and,
and your access, make sure that it's only to systems
that are actually needed for for the workflows that you're building.
We've also got attribute control.
And this is what you can build on to your RBAC.
This is this is things like your no
particular agents just need to access these systems.
They will just be doing it at this time or whatever other attributes.
We can talk about that in the next slide and obviously deny by default.
If if you don't have if
you don't have those permissions in place, you don't want it to be a free for all.
Resource segregation.
This is what's going to be preventing your agents
from accessing data and credentials you don't want them to.
You can you can implement that purely by by by container security controls.
But there's much more that can go wrong there.
Configuring your non users.
You can use your namespace remapping all of that.
It's much safer to use micro VMs using Kata Containers, Firecracker.
There's just less that can go wrong.
Obviously you've got your network ACLs and your egress filtering as well.
Us filtering that fits in with that lethal trifecta and methods.
Rule of two if you if your agents don't need to have internet access,
make sure that you're not allowing that because that obviously
is the an easy route for exfiltrate your data.
And monitoring here we've got here
where you know this has a dependency on the identities you want to be.
Make sure you're logging all events and you've got a clear audit trail.
And the tracing is key as well.
You want to be able to track the track the actions
back to the triggering event which allows for that effective audit trail.
Then you're able to, you know, with these non-deterministic
non-deterministic systems, the actual anomaly detection becomes a key factor.
Here.
You want to be you want to be baseline in what normal operation looks like.
Again, this is why your DevOps dev ops maturity is so important.
Because if you have your environments in good known states, that's
what's allows you to do your anomaly detection.
Once you've got your data points from your baseline in that,
then A enables you to build in your your attribute based access.
Because you've got these
because you've got those locking events and you know what normal looks like.
Here's some resources for for zero trust architecture.
They're sort of ordered by ease of consume ability.
So yeah it recently put out
that PDF which is, which is,
which is really good covers all bases while still being pretty concise.
Then you've got your UCS, NCC, that's some good material
and then good luck with the next one.
But it's, it's got it's got everything you needed
a very granular level.
It is worth having a specific call out
from prompt injection because, you know, you've got two means of prompt injection.
You know what's called direct, which is from
the direct user input into the prompt itself and indirect
through potentially, you know, malicious malicious strings
or commands which are being the data which is then ingested into LLMs
because of how LLMs work in terms of,
you know, they process the instructions and data as tokens
in a, in a context window, those things are indistinguishable.
So there is an argument to be made that you're never able to fully protect
against prompt injection because it's a structural feature of LLMs.
Obviously, you still want to do as much as you can.
The common recommend recommendations there a pattern matching payload filtering,
you know, so things like your input sanitization, your input validation.
You've also got things which are referred to as firewalls
where where you were able to do that before when your users
when your while users are putting things into into the into the prompt.
You've also got output filtering as well.
If you want to catch any sensitive data, you don't want to be coming back to users.
But it's tricky to get to get, especially that.
And that's not going to cover all of the disparate
data sources that potentially being being brought in.
There is a really good research paper
put forward by Microsoft researchers on a technique called spotlighting,
which is which, which a lot of the actual big providers.
So Anthropic are doing this include it does
it does appear to be very effective, but it is not easy to do.
So that's worth reading if you if you if you have
the engineering capability in your org to be able to invest in it.
So everything so far
is all pretty traditional stuff that we know about.
How can we leverage AI and agents to actually make our lives easier and,
and be able to implement, to a mature degree,
something we haven't been able to historically anyway?
So here it's really we need to migrate our,
our security activities to agentic workflows.
We've got attackers using using swarms of agents.
So we need to be able to do the same from a defensive perspective to have a chance.
How are we how we do migrate our security activities
to a workflows is via is via harnesses.
I imagine a lot of you know what harnesses are.
For those that don't, it's effectively a control layer
to scope and orchestrate task carried out by agents.
And we'll look at that in some more depth next.
Cool.
So here's here's a harness composition.
So we've got the control layer.
This is where you're scoping.
You're scoping
what what your specific agents are going to be doing in that workflow.
It also gives you an opportunity to add a human in the loop.
If there's anything you know, you want to have human human interaction
with or approval, and you then got your data plane,
that's when you're going to be defining
what what backend services and data is going to be involved.
And then you've got your agent pipeline.
We're going to have a look at a diagram there.
But that's effectively your your workflow.
When you have a specific agent for that for each task or stage.
Here's an example of what
that looks like from a from a from a pen testing workflow.
You know, we've got the orchestration there at the top.
We've got the shared services layer at the bottom.
So in this example that would be all of your,
all of your, all of your scanning tools that you might be using
pentose would be using.
And here we've got our our pipeline showing the different stages of the
workflows which will be handed off to an agent to workflow
in a very similar way to a CI/CD pipeline execution
would work.
We've got some more examples here of vuln discovery and remediation.
Cloudflare put out a good blog post
a couple of months ago in relation to their, you know, they're
they're they're use in trial with Mythos that outlines
how they, you know, what they put together as a harness to do their own discovery.
We've had some recent, recent open source
harnesses put out there by Capital One and Visa.
And from Snyk we have our own as well.
We've got our Snyk Agent Fix which automatically fixes SAST findings.
Remediation Agent, which automatically fixes SCA findings internally.
We've been we've been spending the last year
migrating our workflows to agentic workflows.
And we've had like real success with with our threat modeling
workflow in particular.
The thing even with even with the most mature
traditional automation threat modeling, automated threat modeling framework
were never able to truly get continuous and scalable
throughout modeling carried out across every change across all projects.
So only really with agents that we've been able to do that,
and now we've been able to close the loop as well by actually instead of
just presenting JIRA stories for the missing controls, we're able
to actually generate the pull request to implement the changes as well.
And that's it.
I just have a question for you.
What other types of
agents could we try to exceed that capability?
Okay.
It's great to be able to the prompt injection.
So do you feel it's
the agent exceeding it's human.
Or could it be a piece of property?
I think it was.
It was specifically around trying to exceed their understanding.
And specifically because they don't have a model, they don't have a world model.
They aren't able to understand what the outcomes of their actions will be.
You know, there's other types of there's other types of models as well.
So things like jointing, bedding models that do build their own world view model.
And so they're able to do
a probabilistic calculation of what the likely consequence of that action is.
So they can make those choices.
Generative LLMs are not able to do that.
It's they don't they don't have they don't have that view.
So you have less reliable outcomes potentially.
They're they're still very capable
and can do lots of things, but they're not necessarily able to pick
the action which is most appropriate.
Unless you're using some
positive critical.
But we take the views of I think opening Hugging Face.
Yeah.
My guess would be it's more because of prompt injection.
So I mean I don't think there was any prompt injection there.
That was that was the agent deciding it.
The best means to achieve the task it was
given was to go and cheat by trying to, by hacking into hugging
face to find the results of the test that it was being evaluated against.
So that wasn't anything to do with prompt injection there.
A example of prompt injection
would be say someone's got so an example of indirect prompt injection.
So someone's connected Claude up to their email.
And someone someone emails them something malicious
because they know it's going to be passed by Claude.
That then triggers something to, you know, send all of my
all of my outbox or all of my inbox to, to someone else.
That would be an example of prompt injection.
Good.
That would be, well, indirect.
Yeah. That's all right.
So the first part,
it's more like a supply chain.
That's yeah it depends.
Yeah I mean it depends depends in the nature of how it got there I suppose.
Yeah.
Thank you.
So it's not from rejection I'm having this issue.
But the agent was trying to do something a cheaper task.
But sometimes patients will respect any promise,
even if you put them in for the talent
to do, they go and do it
like that.
Why do they do that?
Well, ultimately,
ultimately, they're trying to achieve what they've given as their directive.
So that could be based on what they've been.
Going through. And God
said, go through it. Yeah.
Sometimes they don't expect.
Yeah, I mean, that's kind of my argument around you don't rely
on what's in what's in a prompt and what's in the skill.
It doesn't have to go and do that.
Why you need hard, hard gating around
permissions to prevent it, to do what you don't want it to do.
Because, because because of its non-deterministic nature
and you don't know what it's going to choose to do.
I'm sorry.
You two.
On to it.
But what.
I wanted to ask you is how concerned are you about the Chinese Open
models that are coming out like three, for example,
if you look at the entire situation.
Yeah, OpenAI AI had down the guard rails and asked them to do this.
It was exploit German test
and then it's expected containment and went across the face.
I don't know exactly when he played three.
And Qwen might have similar capabilities.
There's no guardrails in those things.
So you know, besides people walking agents and doing that for
my accident is containment.
What about actors using those models to get into the system
for which there about and how concerned as an expert on you about that?
I don't think we can rely on the guide rails anyway because the
the models are only going to get more capable, and we know that
we're not going to have control of the ones which you know of,
of all of them, because all, all the labs are going to be responsible.
So I think how concerned are we about it?
I think
I mean, I mean, I mean, very bitter.
I mean, that's why we need to we need that's why
we can't rely on what we've been doing.
You know, like
traditionally there's not too many places that have got to
have got to a place where they're able to automatically and continuously deploy,
deploy updates to which make sure you're pulling in the latest fixes
for newly discovered funds.
And if you see the rate, if you see the charts for the public CVS,
it's just been going up exponentially now.
So there's much more that can be exploited.
So yeah, it's an arms race to move to for defenders
to move to agentic workflows to be able to plug all the gaps.
And we're going to get very
I mean we're already seeing some happening in some places.
But you're just going to have, you know, agents as autonomous incident
response agents, which are dynamically detecting what what
detections they've got in the same building.
If they don't building them, if they don't have them from the front billing
they've been doing,
then they're going to be creating their own run books if they don't exist,
and then they're going to be acting off that.
It's already it's already happening at the moment.
You know, the OpenAI hugging face.
Then the response to that was via an open an open wait model,
because it didn't have the refusals
to actually generate the fixes for the issues which were identified.
It was GLM 5.2 because they were getting refusals
from I'm not sure which
which GPT, OpenAI model they were trying to use.
I think it was the I think it was like one of the,
one of the cyber ones as well, which was still doing the refusals.
But they were obviously not part of lasting long.
I think they.
Yeah.
Hugging Face that shortly afterwards.
But that's really interesting.
So what type of agents are actually doing the fence as well as what it's going to.
Yeah, that's already in place in some places.
And it just kind of it's just going to become more common.
I mean, the thing which we it's going to be throughout the whole,
the whole engineering, the whole infrastructure stack,
solving all the limiting factors that are stopping us doing it at this moment.
You know, why can't why isn't everyone able to quickly
and reliably deploy changes all the time because of because of immaturity
in their test coverage or of their observability.
So it's just it's creating agents to be able to plug those,
to go and generate the tests where they don't exist, like generate
figure out what's needed from from a metrics perspective from reserve ability.
It's. Yeah.
But I think everyone is from what we're seeing from
from all of our customers.
Everyone is at pace deploying,
deploying agentic workflows and to do exactly that.
Very interesting.
So one last question about their.
Nice nice,
but this is the last
well case.
What happened was the AWS was down
there.
The differences.
So these are basically
you threw for better couldn't find it.
Came back from the rectory.
They couldn't find resources that, you know after cascading.
And they just let the possibilities and everything as well.
But that's, that's, that's, that's
it can happen to anyone that
the question I have is similar.
Why that you shouldn't give assets to general workflows later
in the same that.
It's all you need to do it based on the use case.
But it's the rule of two. Right.
So you if you if you need something to access
if you need to be able to put into agency sensitive information
with widespread access, then then you know, with untrusted
accepting untrusted input as well as sensitive data, then
you want to avoid giving it unrestricted external internet access, basically.
So it's just it's not.
But you will have use cases where your agents will need internet access.
So you just want to make sure you're doing
have some security controls to validate any untrusted input.
So it's not a it's not a you must never do this.
It's whichever is appropriate to cut for.
Your resume.
How to do is outside and domain check it.
It's going to it's going to depend right.
So you might have agents which need to to speak in externally.
But for example maybe you don't give it
unrestricted access to all of your sensitive financial data.
And then also, you know, allow,
allow multiple or allow all of your employees
to be able to ask to ask anything with it from a prompt.
It's going to.
Yeah.
It's not just as simple as don't allow internet.
External internet. Access
is also girls
ages not simply have access
normally. Yeah.
A little less
access.
Cannot access
which place.
you're restricting the internet accessibility
to your databases, you probably want to do the same thing for any agents
which are interacting with that as well, because that's going to be that's
going to be a means of exfiltration via the agents if they've got internet access.
So yeah, you need to figure out what your trust boundaries are
for all the for all of the data flows involved with that.
Like if you if you if you've got something which is just internal
and there's no internet connectivity and then you're adding agents to it,
you want to make sure that those agents don't have
external internet access as well.
Okay,
great.
Thanks.
Yeah, thanks for coming.
Really great events. And I